Hold on, hold on. Before you eat today, listen as these Native Americans describe in full detail the true history of Thanksgiving.
Happy Thanksgiving, America. I'm Donette, and I'm here with my friends to tell you the real history behind this holiday.
Growing up, I knew that what they told you in school about Thanksgiving wasn't true.
That's not the true story.
The true story behind Thanksgiving was, after every killing of a whole village, these European settlers celebrated it, and they called it Thanksgiving.
But it wasn't until Abraham Lincoln became president that it became an official holiday.
He ordered 38 Dakota men to be hung for war crimes after the sacred holiday Christmas.
We take this time to remember our elders who lost their lives due to what really happened.
Usually, my mom makes a Native American dish for us, and we pray.
Growing up, I would be kind of annoyed that they didn't know what actually happened on Thanksgiving,
and that they're actually celebrating the deaths of many people and many tribes that were lost.
Whether it's to give thanks, or to be with your family, you shouldn't learn how that holiday was established in the first place.
I'm thankful for being born Indigenous to this continent.
I'm thankful that I still have my culture.
I'm thankful that my elders kept our culture alive all these years.
I'm thankful to be Indigenous, resilient, and alive.
I'm thankful for us all to be able to stand together, stand strong, and stand as one.
Happy Thanksgiving, America.
Let me know in the comments, what does this day mean to you?
Do you acknowledge it?
Do you celebrate it?
What do your kids know or think about it?
Do you Father?
Do you know how good it is?
Do you practice it?
I'll do you.